Alright
Let's go over what we have in this lesson
The current architecture of our hardware
Because we're about to move on to writing the WEBSOCKET service on the backend
So let's review the overall structure of our hardware
The current architecture
We've done a lot so far
And laid a lot of groundwork
And now we've finally got the framework in place
Let's take a look.
First, we wrote an audio code.
We used this component for the audio code.
It's the component officially provided by Lexin.
This component includes a lot of features.
A combination of these chips.
All sorts of things.
Now, let's look at the code in our architecture.
First, we wrote
This serves as an abstraction layer for the audio.
We provide this abstraction layer.
Because when we instantiate later,
we use a reference to this abstraction layer.
Additionally, we've written a combination here.
Since our current board is assembled in this way,
our hardware drivers,
are written in this combination format in the file.
And this serves as the audio type.
This type
encapsulates the ES8311 and ES72101
two chip combinations
one for playback
and the other for audio capture
these two chips
if your board uses the same combination later
no modifications are needed
you can use this file directly
If you're not, that's fine.
It's like your combination.
This kind of audio combination isn't set up that way.
If you're using 8311, right?
You can directly use it for input and output.
It all uses a single chip.
Then, under this audio setup,
You need to write a file,
To drive the single chip for input and output.
Then, similarly, inherit this class
and implement the methods within this class
provide this method
and when we instantiate it later in this place
we won't need to touch anything inside, right?
we just need to modify this part
let's take a quick look
the audio abstraction layer provides the following methods
let's have a look
It mainly enables audio input
enables audio output
and also closes audio input and output
then plays the audio
we just pass this in
then read the audio
These are the methods for adjusting the volume.
so when we develop applications later
Just focus on these methods.
We don't need to worry about the underlying layer.
In this architecture, we have
a file storage system as well.
We developed a file storage system too.
It's for SD card storage.
We also provide an abstract layer interface here.
This is the interface class.
This interface class is an abstract one.
For audio storage.
This is about file storage.
We use an SD card here.
We implement it using an SD card.
This is where we instantiate it.
Then, we connect this to the IO ports inside.
When we instantiate it here,
it's passed in during the upper-level instantiation.
This way, the code is independent of the hardware.
It's just an SD card driver.
Then, in this context,
the interface provides the following methods:
which is to open a file,
close a file,
and also read from a file,
write to a file,
writing a single line,
select these,
and these are the files we have here.
It encapsulates all the onboard resources.
First, this file, this class
serves as an abstract layer for the board.
It provides a unified method for the application layer.
Here is our board.
This is the driver for our current development board.
If we need to add other boards in the future,
we can create similar folders in this board.
And write your new version of the driver in that folder.
This kind of logic
Then this board serves as an abstraction layer
This is the code
The code here acts as an abstraction layer
And it uniformly provides for
The upper-level abstract resources
The entire set of resources on the board
It uses the singleton pattern
And employs a static factory method
It provides registration for the underlying board
That means we register this board here
It's also instantiation
When it gets instantiated
It retrieves it, but it's not a
Is it using the Singleton pattern?
When retrieving it with the Singleton pattern
It performs a
It retrieves from there
It uses a static factory to create this object, right?
That's correct.
Because it registers it here.
And we configure it through MANUCONFIG.
So when it compiles, it will call the method inside.
It will call the method inside here.
This static factory method.
There can only be one file containing it.
So we'll cover this configuration in a bit.
Let's configure that
Then, in here, we handle the hardware-related configurations
For example, the pin configurations, right
In this section
Within this layer of our board driver
We instantiate the audio object and pass in the audio-related interfaces
It's its IO port
Then, the audio is passed through the audio-related IO ports
First
Then, it also instantiates the file storage object for the SD card.
And it passes the corresponding IO port.
In this way,
we effectively instantiate at the board level.
These,
because only at the board level can we determine which ones are used,
which IO, right?
And there will be display-related components later on,
as well as other related instantiations.
Anyway, the instantiation of the board resources will be placed here.
They will all be placed here.
Then, it provides this to the abstraction layer above.
It provides some interfaces.
Let's take a look.
Currently, this board section provides the following methods:
One is to obtain the audio object.
And to get the file storage object.
These are the two objects we have.
We actually use the audio object for this.
With this method, we can complete our recording and playback.
So, in essence, our entire structure is like this.
The code architecture is as follows.
And our application layer code,
which is our application layer,
is basically written here.
Subsequent code will be written here as well.
And the background tasks we set up earlier are also ready.
This background task primarily handles some
CPU-intensive tasks
which are placed in the background task queue
Regarding compilation-related tasks
we do it this way
we have a KCONFIG here
which we use with menu config
it reads this file
we have a board configuration here
Then, in the configuration menu of this board, there's an option.
This option on the board.
Currently, we're using this development board, right?
The back is white.
And for the ESP32-S3 development board,
if you add new items later,
for new development boards,
you need to add similar entries here.
Add this menu item.
This menu is where you name your development board.
Now, for this part up front,
you can name this macro definition whatever you like.
But once you name it, you need to keep it consistent with the one below.
It needs to be consistent with this one.
The configurations here and here need to match.
After we’ve set this up here,
we also need to write a CMakeLists file here.
In here, we need to add the corresponding macro.
Compilation
Then, this particular configuration here
This configuration is ultimately based on this type
This type is eventually passed here
That means in this folder below
So, you need to do this on the onboard
This is the onboard folder
Then create your new board
The corresponding folder should be the same
We also need to create such a folder
Then inside that folder
Write the corresponding driver for your board
It works like this
Right here
Let's take a look
Whatever name you write here
You need to create a folder with the same name under this board
And in this folder
You should write the driver for your version
This is the overall framework of the current hardware code
It's prepared like this
Now we've organized everything
We're ready to write the backend code
It will be much easier to come back and look at this part
It's very clear, right?
We've organized it
At least now we've got the architecture set up
It will be relatively simple to use it later
Because we can directly use the resources on this board
There are just these two
To get
We don't need to
We don't need to worry about how it gets them right now
We don't need to care about how it operates inside
We just need to call the methods inside, which makes it very simple
Alright, that's it for this lesson